<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Qiaozhi Ye</title>
    <link>https://yegeorge.com/research/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Qiaozhi Ye</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://yegeorge.com/research/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>When Employees Know First:Earnings Information from Retirement Allocations</title>
      <link>https://yegeorge.com/research/employee-ownership/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yegeorge.com/research/employee-ownership/</guid>
      <description>Who knows firms&amp;rsquo; earnings first, and how does that information enter prices? This paper shows that rank-and-file employees incorporate information about contemporaneous earnings into their retirement-saving decisions before markets do. Using U.S. defined-contribution plan data from 2003 to 2023, we find that changes in employee ownership during fiscal year t predict earnings surprises for that same year, which are revealed only when earnings are announced in early year t+1. Stock prices adjust to this information primarily around the announcement window, generating short-lived abnormal returns.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comments that Count: Corporate Influence in SEC Governance Rulemaking</title>
      <link>https://yegeorge.com/research/comments-that-count/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yegeorge.com/research/comments-that-count/</guid>
      <description>We investigate the motivations, effectiveness, and shareholder-value implications of public firms&amp;rsquo; attempts to influence the SEC&amp;rsquo;s governance-related rulemaking. Our analysis leverages large language model-assisted text analysis and citation tracking to examine comment letters submitted during the rulemaking process. We find that public firms predominantly submit pro-management comment letters and that these firms are often associated with weaker governance characteristics. Notably, public firms&amp;rsquo; letters are more likely to be cited in final rules and lead to material changes aligned with their positions particularly when advocating for pro-management changes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Internalizing Environmental Externalities Through Geographic Ownership Networks</title>
      <link>https://yegeorge.com/research/co-and-pollution/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yegeorge.com/research/co-and-pollution/</guid>
      <description>We propose and test the hypothesis that ownership connections between collocating firms facilitate the internalization of environmental externalities. Using the US EPA Toxic Release Inventory data from 1987 to 2019, we find that facilities sharing significant common institutional ownership with nearby firms tend to release fewer toxic chemicals, compared to other facilities of the same parent firm. An analysis using mergers of financial institutions as a quasi-natural experiment suggests that the effect of geographic common ownership on toxic pollution is causal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who Do You Vote For? Same-Race Voting Preferences in Director Elections</title>
      <link>https://yegeorge.com/research/race-and-voting/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yegeorge.com/research/race-and-voting/</guid>
      <description>This paper highlights racial and ethnic preferences in corporate director elections. We discover that mutual fund managers are more likely to vote for director nominees who share their racial or ethnic identity, using a comprehensive dataset of mutual fund voting records. Funds managed by all-white teams exhibit the strongest same-race preference, particularly those in fund families with scarce minority representation. In contrast, minority fund managers exhibit such preference only when voting on candidates nominated to boards with little or no existing minority director representation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Active Mutual Fund Common Owners&#39; Returns and Proxy Voting Behavior</title>
      <link>https://yegeorge.com/research/co-and-return/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yegeorge.com/research/co-and-return/</guid>
      <description>Active equity mutual funds owning shares in product market competitors have higher risk-adjusted returns, even after fees. This positive association comes from their common ownership positions, and remains robust after controlling for industry concentration, common stock selection, and the tendency to invest in firms with more common ownership. These funds charge higher fees and are active voters: more likely to vote against executive pay-for-performance and for directors with existing directorships in competitors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Missing the Boat: Regulatory Approval Delay and Investment Project Outcomes</title>
      <link>https://yegeorge.com/research/regulatory-delay/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yegeorge.com/research/regulatory-delay/</guid>
      <description>By using unique hand-collected project-level investment data on Chinese private investments in public equity (PIPE) issuances, we show that the length of the regulatory approval process for equity issuance is positively related to the probability of subsequent changes in equity-financed projects and a deterioration in project returns. The effects are more pronounced for firms in a highly competitive industry and with a comparative disadvantage. Furthermore, we show that this relationship is causal by exploiting the exogenous shock to approval delay caused by changes in the Chairman of the China Securities Regulation Commission.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
