<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>shareholder voting on Qiaozhi Ye</title>
    <link>https://yegeorge.com/categories/shareholder-voting/</link>
    <description>Recent content in shareholder voting on Qiaozhi Ye</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://yegeorge.com/categories/shareholder-voting/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Internalizing Environmental Externalities Through Geographic Ownership Networks</title>
      <link>https://yegeorge.com/research/co-and-pollution/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yegeorge.com/research/co-and-pollution/</guid>
      <description>We propose and test the hypothesis that ownership connections between collocating firms facilitate the internalization of environmental externalities. Using the US EPA Toxic Release Inventory data from 1987 to 2019, we find that facilities sharing significant common institutional ownership with nearby firms tend to release fewer toxic chemicals, compared to other facilities of the same parent firm. An analysis using mergers of financial institutions as a quasi-natural experiment suggests that the effect of geographic common ownership on toxic pollution is causal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who Do You Vote For? Same-Race Voting Preferences in Director Elections</title>
      <link>https://yegeorge.com/research/race-and-voting/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yegeorge.com/research/race-and-voting/</guid>
      <description>This paper highlights racial and ethnic preferences in corporate director elections. We discover that mutual fund managers are more likely to vote for director nominees who share their racial or ethnic identity, using a comprehensive dataset of mutual fund voting records. Funds managed by all-white teams exhibit the strongest same-race preference, particularly those in fund families with scarce minority representation. In contrast, minority fund managers exhibit such preference only when voting on candidates nominated to boards with little or no existing minority director representation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Active Mutual Fund Common Owners&#39; Returns and Proxy Voting Behavior</title>
      <link>https://yegeorge.com/research/co-and-return/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yegeorge.com/research/co-and-return/</guid>
      <description>Active equity mutual funds owning shares in product market competitors have higher risk-adjusted returns, even after fees. This positive association comes from their common ownership positions, and remains robust after controlling for industry concentration, common stock selection, and the tendency to invest in firms with more common ownership. These funds charge higher fees and are active voters: more likely to vote against executive pay-for-performance and for directors with existing directorships in competitors.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
